A Guide to the Flint Hill Cemetery Collection, 1993
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Flint Hill Cemetery Collection, 1993
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 01-02
1.0 linear feet
The Flint Hill Cemetery Collection consists of 1.0 linear feet and includes individual gravestone surveys of Flint Hill Cemetery and the Oakton Church of the Brethren Cemetery conducted by Jeff Waguespack and Boy Scout Troop 1137, and the Fairfax Genealogical Society in 1993.
Jeff Waguespack and Boy Scout Troop 1137; Fairfax Genealogical Society (Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Jeff Waguespack donated Box 1 containing surveys for sections A and B collected by Waguespack and Troop 1137 in 1993. The Fairfax Genealogical Society donated Box 2 containing surveys for section C and D and the Oakton Church of the Brethren Cemetery in December 1993.
Historical and Biographical Information
Flint Hill Cemetery, located in Oakton, Virginia, dates back to 1852, and is one of Fairfax County’s oldest community cemeteries in addition to being one of the few in the county run by an active association. In 1875, citizens of the community organized the Flint Hill Cemetery Association in order to oversee and maintain the burial ground. As of 2017, the cemetery contains more than 2,300 burials including at least 24 Civil War veterans.
In May 1993, Jeff Waguespack coordinated a survey of sections A and B of Flint Hill Cemetery for his Eagle Project. The labor for the project was drawn from Boy Scout Troop 1137. In the summer and fall of 1993, the Fairfax Genealogical Society surveyed sections C and D of Flint Hill Cemetery and the adjoining Oakton Church of the Brethren Cemetery. Both surveys were donated to the Virginia Room in 1993.
Scope and Content
The Flint Hill Cemetery Collection consists of 1.0 linear feet and includes individual gravestone surveys of Flint Hill Cemetery and the Oakton Church of the Brethren Cemetery conducted by Jeff Waguespack and Boy Scout Troop 1137, and the Fairfax Genealogical Society in 1993. Included are surveys, plat maps and correspondence.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Cemeteries - Virginia - Fairfax County; Fairfax Genealogical Society (Va.); Flint Hill Cemetery (Oakton, Va.); Oakton Church of the Brethren (Oakton, Va.)
Container List
- Plat Maps of Sections A and B, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Section A, Lots 1-10, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Section A, Lots 11-20, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Section A, Lots 21-30, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Section A, Lots 31-40, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Section A, Lots 41-50, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Section A, Lots 51-60, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Section A, Lots 61-70, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Section A, Lots 71-80, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Section A, Lots 81-90, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Section A, Lots 91-100, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Section A, Lots 101-110, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Section A, Lots 111-120, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Section A, Lots 121-130, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Section A, Lots 131-140, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Section A, Lots 141-150, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Section A, Lots 151-160, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Section A, Lots 161-170, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Section A, Lots 171-180, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Section A, Lots 181-190, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Section B, Lots 1-7, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Section B, Lots 8-14, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Section B, Lots 15-21, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Section B, Lots 22-28, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Section B, Lots 29-35, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Section B, Lots 36-42, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Section B, Lots 43-49, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Section B, Lots 50-56, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Section B, Lots 57-63, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Section B, Lots 64-70, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Section B, Lots 71-77, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Section B, Lots 78-84, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Section B, Lots 85-91, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Section B, Lots 92-98, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Section B, Lots 100-106, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Section B, Lots 107-113, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Section B, Lots 114-120, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Section B, Lots 121-127, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Section B, Lots 128-134, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Section B, Lots 135-144, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Section B, Lots 145-148, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Section B, Lots 149-155, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Plat Maps of Section C, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Section C, Lots 1-26, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Section C, Lots 27-33, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Section C, Lots 34-57, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Section C, Lots 58-87, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Section C, Lots 88-117, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Section C, Lots 118-147, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Section C, Lots 148-162, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Section D, Lots 1-6, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Section D, Lots 7-12, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Section D, Lots 13-18, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Oakton Church of the Brethren Cemetery, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)